Hello everyone and welcome back
to English Pod. My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and
today we have an elementary level
lesson about food. One of
my favorite things to talk about.
That's right, we are going
to talk about food, but
specifically we're going to
talk about a family barbecue.
Okay, what is a family barbecue?
We'll all just say a few words.
First, a barbecue is usually
something that we do outside.
We bring food, we play
games, maybe have some
drinks, and a lot of
the food is grilled.
So that's what we're talking
about today. We're going to hear
this dialogue first and then
we'll come back to talk about it.
Is everything ready for the
big family barbecue tomorrow?
Yep, the steaks and chicken are marinated
and they also bought hamburger bums.
We should also cook a couple
dozen hot dogs and kebabs.
Yeah, good idea. We can put some
lawn furniture outside next to the grill.
I also set up the tent outside so we
can hide from the sun if it gets too hot.
Great, I asked Grace to
rain cups and serve yet as
she is also bringing two
big coolers for the beers.
This is going to be a great barbecue.
Oh no, it's rainy.
All right, we're back. So probably a couple
of words you didn't really understand.
So let's take a look at those
now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. Lots
of food where it's Marco.
The first one is barbecue.
We were talking about that
a minute ago. A barbecue
is something we do usually
for something on a special
occasion or for dinner.
It's a summertime thing.
You know, you go outside
when it's warm and the entire
family comes and we have food.
Sometimes people
even bring food. Right.
And actually, as you
mentioned, it's something
that you do a barbecue. You have a
family barbecue, but it's also a verb.
Two barbecue something. So
to cook meat on a barbecue.
So that's cooking meat,
not in a stove, not with gas.
Usually it's under a fire or very
warm intense heat coming from coals.
Exactly. And so before we
cook food, usually before
we cook meat on the
grill before we barbecue it,
we have to marinate it. Okay.
So in this situation, the steaks and
the chicken are already marinated.
Okay. So to marinate
something or which
is so to marinate
something, which is a verb or
the steaks and chickens are
marinated, which is an adjective.
So basically means
that you have added
spices and maybe some
lemon juice, different
herbs or salts to the
meats in order to give it
flavor before you
cook them. Exactly.
Sometimes an Indian cooking,
for example, you marinate with
yogurt sauce and you leave
the meats in the refrigerator
for a whole night.
Exactly. So marinating or
to marinate is a process
to give flavor to food.
Very good. All right. So
we've marinated our food,
our chicken, our steaks,
but also we have hamburgers.
So we need hamburger
buns, which are buns.
Okay. Buns are pieces
of bread that are for
special kinds of food. So
you have a hamburger bun,
it's a round piece of
bread and the hamburger
goes on one piece and
under another piece.
Mm-hmm. A hot
dog bun is different.
It's like a piece of bread that's folded
and the hot dog goes in the middle.
So bun is a special
kind of bread for
these kinds of foods. All
right. So remember, if you
want to have a hot dog, you
need to buy hot dog buns.
So people know already that
you're talking about bread.
And if you want to buy a hamburger bread,
you say a hamburger bun. That's right. So
hamburger buns and hot dog buns.
But after we talk about having
the hamburger buns, we discuss
how many hot dogs are
going to cook. So the person
says, we should cook a
couple dozen hot dogs.
All right. So a dozen is
12 units of something.
Right. So eggs are sold in
dozens. We buy a dozen eggs.
We buy 12 eggs. Okay. Or you can say
half a dozen. That means six, half of 12.
And a couple dozen is
usually around 24/25. Okay.
Very good. So a dozen hot dogs
and they are also getting kebabs.
What are kebabs? One of my favorite foods,
kebabs are sticks or skewers of meat.
So you have a very thin
stick and you put the
meat on it and you put
that on the grill and you
cook the meat on the grill. So
yeah, those are very common.
For example, in the
Middle East, right?
You have kebabs sticks
of meat and also maybe
some vegetables put
on it and you grill them.
Exactly. Very flavorful.
Very tasty meat.
All right. So why don't we
listen to our dialogue again
and we'll come back shortly
to look at some more words.
Is everything ready for the
big family barbecue tomorrow?
Yep. The steaks and chicken are
marinated and I also bought hamburger buns.
We should also cook a couple
dozen hot dogs and kebabs.
Yeah. Good idea. We can
put some lawn furniture
outside next to the
grill. I also set up the tent
outside so we can hide
from the sun if it gets too hot.
Great. I asked Grace
to bring cups and
serve yets as she is also bringing
two big coolers for the beers.
This is going to be
a great barbecue.
All right. We're back. So
now why don't we go to
a second part of language
takeaway and take a look
at five more words.
Language takeaway.
All right. The first word
that we're going to look at
is lawn furniture. So
we're going to have lawn
furniture outside. Okay.
So before we even start
thinking about food,
we have to decide where
people will sit at this
barbecue. And so we have to
find out how much
lawn furniture we have.
Furniture can be a sofa, a table, a
chair. We have furniture in the house.
But lawn furniture is
furniture for the outside.
A lawn is the green
grass outside your house.
So it's usually not going to be made out
of wood, for example, because if it rains,
it might get ruined,
right? So usually it's either
plastic or maybe even rock
or stone or metal or metal.
So that's what lawn
furniture is. Furniture that is
made to be outside in
your backyard, for example,
or that sits on
your lawn. Exactly.
And so we're going to be on a
lawn furniture. We have the special
thing for cooking meat
outside the grill. Okay.
So we mentioned that
you grill chicken or you grill
steaks, but it's also a
noun, a grill. So a grill.
What is that? A grill is
like a stove for the outside,
but instead of having
electricity to make the
fire, we have gas or
propane. And this is something
that we light on fire.
And we use coals to keep
the insides very warm.
And so this is just a way
to cook meats or even
vegetables outside. Okay.
Perfect. So that is a grill.
And if you're going to
cook foods or vegetables
in this way, so you're
going to grill them. All
right. And well, just in
case it gets hot and
you want to hide from the
sun, we are going
to set up a tent. Okay.
A tent, you can sleep in a
tent, but in this case, a tent
is just a covering outside.
So maybe some cloth or
some fabric that will
stand over us when we sit
down or want to be
outside. It's also a way to
protect us from the rain. Right.
So as you mentioned, a tent
is something that you set up
temporarily made out of
cloth or plastic to protect
you from the sun or rain. Or if you're
going camping, you sleep in one. All right.
And now that they have
all the food, they need cups,
and then they mentioned the strange word.
It kind of sounds French. Serviettes.
Serviettes. So I do think it
comes from the French word.
This is a British way
of saying napkins.
And now it's like paper
for cleaning your hands
and cleaning your mouth
that you throw away.
Okay. So you can say
napkins or if you want to
sound a little bit more
fancier, you can say Serviettes.
And speaking of fancy,
let's talk about beer.
Where do we, where
do we keep beer?
It has to stay
cold, right? Right.
So usually you would
place it in a refrigerator,
but if you're outside or
you're going camping,
you want to keep them
cold or you want to keep
something hot, you
place it in a cooler. Okay.
So cooler is a plastic
bin or a plastic box
that we put all of the
ice in and the drinks.
So it's not just for beer.
It's also for coke and
and Sprite and all these
different drinks. Right.
So it's usually made
to keep something cool.
But as I said, if you
want to keep something
warm, you can also
keep it in the cooler.
It keeps the temperature of
the foods. And the nice thing
is that it's not electric. So
you can use it anywhere.
Right. All right. So that's
all the words for today.
Why don't we listen to our
dialogue for the last time.
Is everything ready for the
big family barbecue tomorrow?
Yep. The steaks and chicken are marinated
and they also bought hamburger buns.
We should also cook a couple
dozen hot dogs and kebabs.
Yeah, good idea. We could
put some lawn furniture
outside next to the
grill. I also set up the tent
outside so we can hide
from the sun if it gets too hot.
Great. I asked Grace to
bring cups and serve yet.
She is also bringing two big
coolers for the beers. This is
going to be a great barbecue.
Oh no. It's rainy.
All right. We're back.
So family barbecues and
doing these things. Did you do
these when you were young at home?
Do you still like to do it?
All the time. I love barbecues.
That's one of my favorite
ways to eat food.
The nice thing about a
barbecue is you get to
sit outside and relax and
there's nothing better than
a nice fresh grilled meat.
Right. And well, you have
it all your friends over.
So you're having a
couple of beers and
you're having some meat.
And it's actually a really
nice way of just having
something at home with
good friends and
family. Right. Exactly.
And some of the most important
barbecues we have are in
the summer near July
4th. And so people like to
have July 4th barbecues
where you celebrate
Independence Day and sit
outside and drink and have
hot dogs and hamburgers
and macaroni and cheese.
Actually, well, that wasn't
chilly. I noticed that as well.
Near their festivities
for their independence,
which is September
18th, a lot of people get
together and have barbecues.
And it's so, so popular
that pretty much every
house in the neighborhood
you can smell somebody
barbecuing on the weekend.
You're making me so
hungry. All right, guys,
so if you have any
questions, any doubts, or if
it's common for you guys
to barbecue back home,
then why don't you send us a
couple of comments at englishpot.
com. And we'll see
you everyone there. Bye.